<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sweet Peonies</title>
    <description>Simple ideas for everyday living</description>
    <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sweetpeonies.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 17:14:24 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 17:14:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Raspberry Drop Chocolate Cupcakes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend the hubby and I had our first outing with friends in Austin. After two weeks of unpacking, rearranging, exploring, getting stuck in traffic, filling out paperwork, and getting stuck in more traffic we were invited to dinner by a fellow PhD student from Jack’s program. Our task: dessert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-21-raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes/raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Drop Chocolate Cupcakes - Sweet Peonies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to branch out from my typical go-to desserts and make something new. Austin’s fresh, organic fruits and vegetables have completely won me over so I wanted to make a dessert that would highlight one of these beauties. The result? Raspberry drop chocolate cupcakes. With a hint of coffee and a fresh juicy raspberry baked into the center, the cupcakes were covered in rich chocolate frosting and finally sprinkled with lemon zest. Unfortunately, the Texas heat turned my frosting into more of a glaze but they were still incredibly satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-21-raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes/raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Drop Chocolate Cupcakes - Sweet Peonies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipe I used comes from a magazine the hubby bought for me a while back, “&lt;em&gt;Taste of Home&lt;/em&gt; 100 Best Desserts.” I altered a few minor ingredients and instructions. The original recipe called for a drop of seedless raspberry jam in the center but I wanted the tangy flavor of a fresh raspberry instead. I also left out the coffee liquor in the frosting, mainly because I didn’t have any, but also because the added liquid would not help the frosting harden in this heat. My last change was adding the lemon zest on top. It seems small and perhaps insignificant but I loved the faint hint of lemon and raspberry with every bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-21-raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes/raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Drop Chocolate Cupcakes - Sweet Peonies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipe said it made 2 1/2 dozen cupcakes, but I would estimate it making closer to 3 1/2 dozen. I filled my cupcake liners 2/3 full and after 2 dozen, still had close to half the batter leftover. My last observation, the batter looked more liquid-y than any other cupcake recipe I have used. I was very skeptical that it wouldn’t cook in the time allotted but they cooked perfectly. So, if you are anything like me and tend to change recipes before seeing them through to completion, &lt;em&gt;don’t do it&lt;/em&gt;. Trust me, you will be pleasantly surprised on this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-21-raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes/raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Drop Chocolate Cupcakes - Sweet Peonies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave you with the recipe now while I figure out what to do with 3 1/2 dozen cupcakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Raspberry Drop Chocolate Cupcakes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Batter&lt;/em&gt;
1 c. baking cocoa
2 c. boiling water
1 c. butter, softened
2 1/2 c. sugar
4 eggs
2 tbsp cold brewed coffee
2 tsp vanilla
2 3/4 c. flour
2 tsp baking soda
1/2 tsp baking powder
1/2 tsp salt
1 small package fresh raspberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frosting&lt;/em&gt;
1 can coconut milk (13.6 oz)
1 pkg. dark chocolate chips (12 oz)
1/2 c. butter, cubed
1/3 c. confectioners sugar
1 lemon (to zest)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend beginning with the frosting, which is supposed to refrigerate for 1 1/2 hours, a detail I missed on the first read-through. Translation: long pause between cupcakes being complete and being able to chow down on the finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoon 1 cup of cream from the top of coconut milk and place into a saucepan to boil. Once the cream starts to boil, remove from heat and add chocolate chips, whisking smooth. Stir in butter and confectioner’s sugar. Refrigerate for 1 1/2 hrs or until well chilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to the cupcakes, preheat the oven to 350 degrees. In a small bowl, combine cocoa and boiling water and set aside to cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a second bowl, cream the softened butter and sugar until fluffy. Add eggs one at a time until well combined. Add coffee and vanilla. Combine flour, salt, baking powder &amp;amp; soda and add to creamed mixture alternately with cocoa mixture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill cupcake liners 2/3 full, drop a whole raspberry into the center (no need to push it down, just set on top and the batter will cook up around it). Bake for 18-20 minutes, until toothpick comes out clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool for at least 10 minutes before frosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the frosting has chilled, beat mixture until soft peaks form. They said this should take about 15 seconds. We had to take ours out of the fridge early due to poor planning and so it took longer than 15 seconds to see soft peaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frost cupcakes. Grate lemon zest over frosting and top it all off with another raspberry. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/08/21/raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/08/21/raspberry-drop-chocolate-cupcakes</guid>
        
        
        <category>Baking</category>
        
        <category>Cake</category>
        
        <category>Cupcakes</category>
        
        <category>Food</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Barton Creek Greenbelt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With only a couple of weeks until classes start again for the husband, we are determined to make the most of the beautiful weather and our remaining free time. Sadly, hiding out in the comforts of an air conditioned home in Texas in the middle of the summer sounds and feels all too enticing. Today however, we laced up our hiking boots and set out in search of new adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, our lazy Saturday morning attitude came back to bite us in the caboose and we didn’t get out to the trails until almost noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s adventures took us to Austin’s Barton Creek Greenbelt. The trails have large limestone cliffs, dense foliage and shallow bodies of water (although today, they were dry-as-a-bone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you (like me) who have never heard of a greenbelt, it is a protected natural or semi-natural environment around an urban area. Barton Creek is maintained by the Parks and Recreation Department of Austin and is meant to improve air quality, provide urban residents with access to countryside and outdoor recreation, and give character to urban areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was nearly noon by the time we arrived at the trails, our hike and “go-get-em attitudes” didn’t last long. However, I wouldn’t leave without snapping a few photos to share with you all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more adventures from Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-17-barton-creek-greenbelt/barton-creek-greenbelt-13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Barton Creek Greenbelt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/08/17/barton-creek-greenbelt</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/08/17/barton-creek-greenbelt</guid>
        
        
        <category>Austin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Heart of Texas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Austin welcomed us with open arms and hot weather last week. The city recorded 15 days over 100 degrees and while this heat is causing even the locals to think twice about heading outdoors, the husband and I are LOVING it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought today I would simply share a few photos of downtown Austin and the capitol building. Be warned, these were taken on the hubby’s ipod from a moving car. We’re hoping to take the camera out on a stroll this weekend so stay tuned for more pictures and hopefully some exciting discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-15-the-heart-of-texas/the-heart-of-texas-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Heart of Texas&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-15-the-heart-of-texas/the-heart-of-texas-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Heart of Texas&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-08-15-the-heart-of-texas/the-heart-of-texas-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Heart of Texas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to lots of Texan adventures, y’all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/08/15/the-heart-of-texas</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/08/15/the-heart-of-texas</guid>
        
        <category>Austin</category>
        
        
        <category>Austin</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mango Avocado Salsa &amp; Chili-Coke Chicken</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Austin Countdown: T-17 days. That’s right, in just two weeks the hubby and I will be packing the wagons and heading to the big land of Texas where Jack will work hard on his PhD and I will lounge lazily by the pool, work on my tan and eat Fro-Yo. Have I mentioned I am still unemployed? Hopefully that will change soon after we get settled and then off to work for me as well. Now, on to more tasty topics…With most of our home packed into boxes, there have been few projects for me to share with you, that is, until this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack and I have been on a constant scouting mission for avocados. Avocados are my all time favorite summer food. Unfortunately, finding these delicious fruits is easier said than done. Produce options are ridiculously limited in our small town and when we do find a decent batch, they typically sell for around $2/fruit. Yikes! Lately, our local produce stand down the street has had a fairly good showing of avocado however and we have been taking full advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-07-17-mango-avocado-salsa-chili-coke-chicken/mango-avocado-salsa-chili-coke-chicken-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mango Avocado Salsa &amp;amp; Chili-Coke Chicken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, we had avocado every night. Since the weather here is hot and sticky, we wanted our meal to highlight the avocado flavor and also remain light and fresh tasting. Here’s what we came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mango Avocado Salsa &amp;amp; Chili-Coke Chicken over Spinach and a Toasted Tortilla&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sounds long and complicated as I write it out but it is pretty simple and incredibly delicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-07-17-mango-avocado-salsa-chili-coke-chicken/mango-avocado-salsa-chili-coke-chicken-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mango Avocado Salsa &amp;amp; Chili-Coke Chicken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chili-Coke Chicken&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 chicken breasts
1 tbsp red pepper flakes
1 tbsp Adobo seasoning
2 tbsp Brown sugar
pepper to taste
coke to taste –start at 1 tsp
rum to taste –start at 1 tsp
2 tsp lemon juice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boil 2 chicken breasts until cooked. Run cold water over chicken and shred. Mix above ingredients, adjust according to taste. All our sauces are done by taste so these are rough measurements. Toss chicken with seasoning and let sit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-07-17-mango-avocado-salsa-chili-coke-chicken/mango-avocado-salsa-chili-coke-chicken-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mango Avocado Salsa &amp;amp; Chili-Coke Chicken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mango Avocado Salsa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Mango
1 Avocado
1/4 cup chopped red onion
1/8 cup chopped fresh cilantro
1/4 cup yellow tomato chopped
1/4 Feta Cheese
1 tsp lemon juice
salt and pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine ingredients by tossing gently. Set Aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, pour 1-2 tsp of olive oil into a pan. Allow the oil to warm up and then toss your tortilla into the oil. Cook on each side until slightly crisp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pile spinach on top of the tortillas, followed by the chicken and topped off with the mango avocado salsa. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/07/17/mango-avocado-salsa-chili-coke-chicken</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/07/17/mango-avocado-salsa-chili-coke-chicken</guid>
        
        <category>Avocado</category>
        
        <category>Fresh Vegetables</category>
        
        <category>Mango</category>
        
        <category>Summer Meal</category>
        
        
        <category>Cooking</category>
        
        <category>Food</category>
        
        <category>Vegetables</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer Refreshments: Mojitos</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing quite compares to the thrill of that first refreshing splash of summer. The anticipation as you drive toward the lake, the squeal of delight as your toes dip playfully at the water’s edge and the rush of adrenaline as you hold your breath and dive on in. The humid summers of East Tennessee have made me appreciate more fully the therapeutic refreshment that water brings. Whether it be by poolside, lake, river, or ocean, water gives us a chance to beat the heat, both literally or figuratively. Although for many the mayhem of work continues into the summer, the endless heat eventually beckons people out of their cubicles, into their cars, and toward the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we can’t spend every moment of summer lakeside with a drink in hand, we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; find some satisfaction in the refreshments of summer. I’m talking Mojitos, people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-06-19-summer-refreshments-mojitos/summer-refreshments-mojitos-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Virgin Mojitos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hubby and I have been experimenting with different refreshing cocktails this summer, and while I’m always game for the traditional Mojito, I wanted to try an alcohol-free version that would taste light, refreshing and full of summer. Today I attempted a Mojito spritzer. There is no fancy trick to this little number, just simple minty deliciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recipe:&lt;/em&gt;
1 oz simple syrup/1oz lime juice (Cheat: 2 oz Mojito Mix)
10 Mint Leaves
3 oz Club Soda
1 tsp. brown sugar
Ice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To Mix:&lt;/em&gt;
Grind fresh mint leaves with brown sugar in separate bowl and place in shaker. Place ice in cocktail shaker. Add Mojito Mix or simple syrup and lime juice. Shake. Pour into glass. Add club soda. If you prefer less minty flavor, simply add more club soda or you can always add rum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-06-19-summer-refreshments-mojitos/summer-refreshments-mojitos-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Virgin Mojitos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/06/19/summer-refreshments-mojitos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/06/19/summer-refreshments-mojitos</guid>
        
        <category>Mojitos</category>
        
        
        <category>Cocktails</category>
        
        <category>Cooking</category>
        
        <category>Food</category>
        
        <category>Home</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bold &amp; Beautiful Bridal Bouquet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For some individuals, creativity seems to pour out with ease, turning everything they touch into creativity gold. For others, coming up with something creative is a more labored, time consuming process requiring hours of research scouring blogs and reading articles, testing recipes, practicing new techniques, ruining much anticipated projects, writing and rewriting, taking photo after photo after photo… Can you guess which one of these categories I fall into?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right. I’m a “creativity is a painstaking process” personality and I wouldn’t trade it for the world. Because I have tried and failed at so many projects, I have branched out and discovered the world of creativity is ginormous! From childhood to now I’ve dabbled in drawing, beading, photography, scrapbooking, painting, cooking, sewing, baking, woodworking, furniture restoration, interior design, blogging, violin, photography again, flowers, flowers and more flowers. With so many different avenues to explore, how could I possibly settle on just one? If I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; choose just one creative venture, perhaps I would find myself excelling, but until that day, the randomness of my projects will continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-06-16-bold-beautiful-bridal-bouquet/bold-beautiful-bridal-bouquet-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bold Bridal Bouquet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to what you all are wanting to see, flowers! Unfortunately, as Jack and I prepare for our big move to Austin, my time on the farm has slowed significantly. However, Kristin and I recently arranged a wedding for a Tennessee bride. The table arrangements were fairly simple–three wine bottles with three different arrangements in each. The showstopper was the bride’s bouquet (thank you Kristin). Kristin’s finished design was exquisite. We decided to wrap the stems in simple burlap with three pearl pins so nothing took away from the beautiful colors. The finished product: a bold and beautiful bridal bouquet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2013-06-16-bold-beautiful-bridal-bouquet/bold-beautiful-bridal-bouquet-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bold Bridal Bouquet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/06/16/bold-beautiful-bridal-bouquet</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/06/16/bold-beautiful-bridal-bouquet</guid>
        
        <category>Brides Bouquet</category>
        
        <category>Wedding</category>
        
        
        <category>Flowers</category>
        
        <category>In The Garden</category>
        
        <category>The Farm</category>
        
        <category>Wedding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Back to the Flowers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/06/back-to-the-flowers/me-2/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/05/Me-575x805.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flower Farm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s flower time on the farm! The hubby and I are preparing for a big move to the big land of Texas, of course that’s not about to stop me from enjoying a few last summer days on the farm. I spent the morning with my dear friend Kristin getting ready for a wedding this weekend. Linda was able to sneak away on a little vacation, so while she’s away, we get to play! Stay tuned this weekend for snapshots of our arranging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I must have flowers, always, and always.&lt;/em&gt; ― Claude Monet&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/06/05/back-to-the-flowers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/06/05/back-to-the-flowers</guid>
        
        
        <category>Art</category>
        
        <category>Flowers</category>
        
        <category>In The Garden</category>
        
        <category>Photographs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It’s Graduation Thyme!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is finally here, after 7 long years of dedicated studies I am finally graduating with my BSN degree! I must apologize for the lack of posting this semester, my mother’s mantra still rings in my head, “studies come first,” and so, blogging has taken a back seat. However, with graduation less than a week away I wanted to share with you a few images from my graduation celebration wishlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following are ideas I’ve combined to make a Graduation Thyme Garden Party Celebration come to life. I hope these ideas spark your creativity as you prepare for your own graduation celebrations in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 407px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![Minted garden party invitations](http://cdn4.minted.com/2012/03/25/22/59/38/814aa01f638c233d5d37b161ad6555cc)](http://cdn4.minted.com/2012/03/25/22/59/38/814aa01f638c233d5d37b161ad6555cc)

Garden Party Invitations via Minted

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 510px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![Herb Favor Bags](http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m385z8YChW1rnzm2eo1_500.png)](http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m385z8YChW1rnzm2eo1_500.png)

Herb Favor Bags via Move Nourish Believe

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 234px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![Garden Party Tablescape](http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-eF3b-0f73FI/T_4KhSUifqI/AAAAAAAAJD4/VoC7BH-FSsU/s320/farmhouse+bbq.png)](http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-eF3b-0f73FI/T_4KhSUifqI/AAAAAAAAJD4/VoC7BH-FSsU/s320/farmhouse+bbq.png)

The Tablescape via HeatherBullard.com

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 600px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![Brioche, Peaches, Thyme garden party treat](http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-tByu_GTDl0Q/US--dZV9V1I/AAAAAAAAECo/cbbYG4xCOtc/s1600/drozdzowki+z+brzoskwinia.jpg)](http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-tByu_GTDl0Q/US--dZV9V1I/AAAAAAAAECo/cbbYG4xCOtc/s1600/drozdzowki+z+brzoskwinia.jpg)

Brioche, Peaches and Thyme via Bayaderka

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 560px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![bagel bar](http://static.weddingchicks.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/bagelbar.jpg)](http://static.weddingchicks.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/bagelbar.jpg)

Bagel Bar via Wedding Chicks

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 370px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![Good Ideas for You summer garden party ideas](http://goodideasforyou.com/images/igallery/resized/22601-22700/15762667415306387_1IwBLkQu_f-22656-900-500-80-c.jpg)](http://goodideasforyou.com/images/igallery/resized/22601-22700/15762667415306387_1IwBLkQu_f-22656-900-500-80-c.jpg)

Flowers and Paper Bags via Good Ideas For You

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 558px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![Onto Baby Vintage Couples Shower](http://www.ontobaby.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/handmade-vintage-couples-shower-2.jpg)](http://www.ontobaby.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/handmade-vintage-couples-shower-2.jpg)

Juice Bar (but add champagne for a mimosa bar) via Onto Baby

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 437px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![Thyme garden party decor](http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_V_qSgJvLF30/TFMwFZtrNFI/AAAAAAAACBA/ZhtGMndWfQ8/s640/IMG_4204.JPG)](http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_V_qSgJvLF30/TFMwFZtrNFI/AAAAAAAACBA/ZhtGMndWfQ8/s640/IMG_4204.JPG)

Drying Thyme via French Larkspur

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 672px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;[![Berry Tart](http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8294/7548843566_1edbf614d2_b.jpg)](http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8294/7548843566_1edbf614d2_b.jpg)

Berry Tarts via Belonika

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/05/05/its-graduation-thyme</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/05/05/its-graduation-thyme</guid>
        
        <category>Garden Party</category>
        
        <category>Graduation</category>
        
        <category>Party</category>
        
        
        <category>Baking</category>
        
        <category>Crafts</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
        <category>Flowers</category>
        
        <category>In The Garden</category>
        
        <category>Links</category>
        
        <category>Photographs</category>
        
        <category>Tarts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Diaper Burp Cloths DIY</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s springtime here in Tennessee and I could not be more pleased!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of my favorite things about Spring:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;1.) Dew on the grass every morning&lt;br /&gt;
2.) Sunshine and blue skies&lt;br /&gt;
3.) Tiny flower buds sprouting up through the ground&lt;br /&gt;
4.) Planting my garden&lt;br /&gt;
5.) Grilling out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spring, like many before, has already been filled with a plethora of baby showers (all boys). I always know spring is coming when the baby shower invitations begin to roll in. In the past 2 weeks I have had 4 baby showers to attend and I must say, this quickly exhausts my creative abilities and available time trying to come up with something cute and unique for each person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/diaper-burp-cloths/diaperburpcloths-6/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/diaperburpcloths-6-575x384.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;diaper burp cloth; diy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I’ve decided to try out the famous redesigned diaper burp cloths. I always like this idea but up until a few weeks ago had never actually tried my hand at crafting these sweet gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/diaper-burp-cloths/diaperburpcloths-10/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/diaperburpcloths-10-575x384.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;diaper burp cloth; diy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I purchased a couple packs of pre-folded cloth diapers from osocozy.com. They also have flat diapers if you prefer the shape. I found that the pre-folded diapers provide clean lines to measure &amp;amp; match to my printed fabric. Next I purchased a fairly inexpensive pack of three receiving blankets, also pre-folded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/diaper-burp-cloths/diaperburpcloths-5/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/diaperburpcloths-5-575x384.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;diaper burp cloth; diy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three sections made by the folds in the receiving blanket perfectly matched the width of the three sections on my diapers. This made it simple to cut three strips out of the receiving blankets and place one in the center strip of the diaper. Once in place, I folded under the edges of the receiving blanket and pinned in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/diaper-burp-cloths/diaperburpcloths-7/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/diaperburpcloths-7-575x384.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;diaper burp cloth; diy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I chose a fancy hem design from my sewing machine and sewed around the edges of the receiving blanket fabric, making sure half of the stitch was on the blanket and half off as I stitched around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/diaper-burp-cloths/diaperburpcloths-3/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/diaperburpcloths-3-575x381.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;diaper burp cloth; diy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it! If you cut all our strips first then place, fold and pin all together, then sew all together, you can whip up about 6 of these in less than 1 hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/diaper-burp-cloths/diaperburpcloths-12/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/diaperburpcloths-12-575x381.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;diaper burp cloth; diy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I was very pleased with this project and look forward to trying more variations in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/diaper-burp-cloths/diaperburpcloths-9/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/diaperburpcloths-9-575x381.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;diaper burp cloths, diy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/04/09/diaper-burp-cloths</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/04/09/diaper-burp-cloths</guid>
        
        <category>Baby Shower</category>
        
        <category>Diaper Burp Cloths</category>
        
        <category>Diy</category>
        
        <category>Gift</category>
        
        
        <category>Baby</category>
        
        <category>Crafts</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
        <category>Sewing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sailor Baby Shower</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple weekends ago, I had the pleasure of helping out with baby shower decorations for my sweet friend Jane. Her and the hubster are expecting their first child in the next few weeks. My friend Kristin and I decided to broaden the trendy whale baby shower theme to a sailor baby shower. Instead of cutesy whales, we went with boyish flags in bold colors and homemade life preservers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/sailor-baby-shower/sailorshower-1/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/sailorshower-1-575x359.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sailor Shower; baby shower&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kristin found these awesome nautical signal flag patterns at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purlbee.com/the-purl-bee/2011/6/26/lauras-loop-nautical-flag-napkins.html&quot;&gt;PurlBee: Laura’s Loop&lt;/a&gt;. The ones on the site are napkins, ours were simply flags made out of felt squares. To assemble, we cut strips of felt and hot glued them onto larger blocks of felt, making a flag for each letter of the alphabet. The life preservers are from a picture Kristin found on Pinterest. Unfortunately there was not a usable link to share with you. To assemble we used 2 foam rings, cut them in half to make 4 rings and wrapped white and red streamers around them to make little life preservers. Linda from &lt;a href=&quot;http://auntwillieswildflowers.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Aunt Willie’s Wildflowers&lt;/a&gt; brought the daffodils in blue vases to place in the center of the life preservers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/sailor-baby-shower/sailorshower-2/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/sailorshower-2-575x359.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sailor shower; baby shower; paper boats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the adorable origami paper boats at &lt;a href=&quot;http://ilovethisandthat.blogspot.com/2013/03/origami-paper-boat.html&quot;&gt;I Love This and That&lt;/a&gt;. I used colored printer paper and cardstock instead of the vellum and cut my paper to 5×7.5in. I would recommend using paper no thicker than printer paper, the cardstock boats were a bit more difficult to fold once you get to the last steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food selection consisted of a beautiful,colorful &amp;amp; tasty salad bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/sailor-baby-shower/sailorshower-3/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/sailorshower-3-575x359.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;salad bar; baby shower; sailor theme&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, of course, what baby shower is complete without the mother-to-be and all her friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sweetpeonies.com/2013/04/sailor-baby-shower/sailorshower-4/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;jekyll_uploads/2013/04/sailorshower-4-575x359.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;baby shower; sailor theme&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/04/02/sailor-baby-shower</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sweetpeonies.com/blog/2013/04/02/sailor-baby-shower</guid>
        
        <category>Sailor Theme</category>
        
        <category>Baby Shower</category>
        
        <category>Sea</category>
        
        <category>Nautical</category>
        
        <category>Flags</category>
        
        <category>Paper Boat</category>
        
        
        <category>Baby</category>
        
        <category>Crafts</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
